Princeton University Library Collection of Ashbel Green Materials, 1744-1958 (bulk 1783-1848): Finding Aid C0257
Manuscripts Division
Princeton University Library Collection of Ashbel Green Materials
1744-1958
1783-1844
Manuscripts Division
Green, Ashbel, 1762-1848.
C0257
13 boxes
4.84 linear feet
Ashbel Green (1762-1848) was a prominent Presbyterian minister, eighth president of the College of New Jersey, and co-founder of the Princeton Theological Seminary. The bulk of the papers consist of Green's personal writings, including diaries and sermons. The papers of Green's father, the Reverend Jacob Green (1722-1790) are also included.
Biographical / Historical
Born in Hanover, New Jersey, on July 6, 1762, Ashbel Green was the son of the Reverend Jacob Green, minister of the Presbyterian congregation in Hanover. Taught at home by his father, Green adopted many of his father's religious and political convictions. Green credited his father with adequately preparing him for college. He entered the College of New Jersey (now Princeton University) as a member of the Class of 1783 during that class's junior year. He graduated as valedictorian and delivered the valedictory oration. After graduation, Green spent two years as a tutor at the college followed by a year and a half as the chair of the Mathematics and Natural Philosophy department. While working at the college, Green was also studying theology with Professor John Witherspoon with the goal of becoming a minister in mind. Green would also marry his first wife, Elizabeth Stockton, while at the College of New Jersey. Elizabeth was the daughter of prominent Princetonian Robert Stockton. They had three children together – Robert Stockton, Jacob, and James Sprout.
Green was licensed to preach by the Presbytery of New Brunswick in February 1786. He was ordained and installed minister at Philadelphia's Second Presbyterian Church in May of 1787, where he remained until 1812. While a minister in Philadelphia, Green's stature began to grow. He became a member of the Presbyterian General Assembly, later serving as its Stated Clerk from 1790 to 1803. He achieved national prominence when he was elected chaplain to the U.S. House of Representatives in 1792, where he served until the end of President Washington's second term in 1800. He was a member of the committee which planned the Theological Seminary at Princeton and maintained a close relationship with the institution until his death.
Green was elected president of the College of New Jersey in August 1812, succeeding Samuel Stanhope Smith (1751-1819). Unhappy with the direction the previous administration had taken the college, Green sought to reestablish order and discipline and the importance of religious education. The campus underwent a modest religious revival not long after he took office. Frequent student riots had plagued the college during President Smith's tenure, prompting Green to implement a firm code of discipline. Though student discontent persisted, Green was successful in increasing enrollment during his tenure. He resigned in September of 1822, prompted by the trustees' attempts to push his son Jacob out of his professorship. Green also cited illness and age as contributing factors. After leaving Princeton, Green returned to Philadelphia to edit the Christian Advocate and continue his career as an influential theologian.
Green's first wife died in January of 1807. In October 1809, Green married Christina Anderson, daughter of Colonel Alexander Anderson. Ashbel and Christina had one child, Ashbel, Jr. Christina passed away in 1814. In 1815 he married a third time to Mary McCulloh, who died in 1817. Green lived to age 86, passing away on May 19, 1848, in Philadelphia.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of writings, correspondence, printed documents, and other materials of Green. Included are Green's original diaries (with typed transcriptions), covering the period from 1790 to 1848, as well as holograph reports, sermons, and addresses. The reports were delivered to the faculty and trustees of the College of New Jersey and describe the state of the college in a given year. Most of the sermons, numbered and dated and noting a specific Bible verse, were intended for Green's congregation in Philadelphia.
Correspondence documents Green's personal and professional activities through letters exchanged over the course of his life with family, friends, and colleagues. Correspondents include Green's wives, children, work associates, and fellow clergymen, as well as several prominent Americans of the time, such as Francis Scott Key, Dr. Benjamin Rush, and Jedediah Morse.
In addition, the papers include printed material, such as copies of The Life of Ashbel Green (1849) and a collection of sermons from the Christian Advocate. There are also documents created by Green's father, Jacob Green (1722-1790), and various other family members.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The initial accession occurred in March 1958 when the bulk of the Jacob Green and some Ashbel Green material was given to Princeton as a gift from James L. and Beverly Green. Several Ashbel Green letters were added in 1976 as a gift from Mr. and Mrs. Joseph Outerbridge. In 1977, Princeton received letters and documents related to Ashbel Green and Dr. Samuel McCulloh as a gift from Mary McCulloch. The Ashbel Green diaries, transcripts, genealogical sketch, the copy of The Life of Ashbel Green, and 8 letters from Green to various family members was purchased by Princeton from Geoffrey Stockton Green in August 1989. "Resolutions on entering on duty of president, Princeton College" and "Extract of minutes of meetings of the Synod of New York and New Jersey" were purchased in 2006 from a private dealer.
Accruals
No accruals are expected.
Appraisal
No appraisal information is available.
Related Materials
The Seeley G. Mudd Manuscript Library holds material related to Ashbel Green in the Office of the President Records.
Bibliography
A Princeton Companion (Princeton: Princeton University Press, 1978) and The Life of Ashbel Green, V.D.M. (New York: Robert Carter and Brothers, 1849) were consulted during preparation of biographical note.
Clergy -- United States.; Fathers and sons -- New Jersey -- Princeton.; Princeton University -- Riot, 1817.; Correspondence -- 18th century.; Correspondence -- 19th century.; Diaries -- 18th century.; Diaries -- 19th century.; Speeches.; Sermons, American -- 18th century.; Sermons, American -- 19th century.; American history/Early national; Princeton University; Green, Ashbel, 1825-1898.; Green, Jacob, 1722-1790.; Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.; Princeton University -- Alumni and alumnae -- 18th century.; Princeton University -- Faculty -- 19th century.; Princeton University -- Presidents -- 19th century.
- Series 1: Writings, 1764-1848; 9 boxes
  Conditions Governing Access
  The collection is open for research.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of the personal writings of Ashbel Green. It contains four subseries. The first, Diaries, includes both hand written and typed transcripts of Green's personal diaries. The second, Reports, includes hand written drafts and completed reports addressed to the faculty and trustees of the College of New Jersey. The third, Sermons, includes hand written and numbered sermons delivered by Green. The fourth, Miscellaneous, includes photostats of portions of the "Life of Witherspoon" and several addresses, which written and read while Green was president of the College of New Jersey.
  Arrangement
  The subseries are arranged alphabetically.
  - Subseries 1A: Diaries, 1790-1848; 8 boxes
    This subseries consists of the personal diaries of Ashbel Green. Included are both hand written, bound volumes and typed transcripts. Green started keeping a diary 1790 and continued the practice until his death in 1848. The bulk of the entries consist of brief notes Green's activities for the day. He noted eating and sleeping habits, visits or trips he took, tasks he may have accomplished, and his prayer schedule. Occasionally, Green commented on his mood, discussed future plans, or offered his thoughts on a particular subject. Items of interest include Green's thoughts and expectations on becoming the Chaplain of the House of Representatives in 1792, his description of his arrival at Princeton and the details of the creation of the Theological Seminary in 1812, the details on the student riots in 1817, and his thoughts on his decision to resign as president of the College of New Jersey in 1822. The bound volumes contain some entries in Green's shorthand. The pages in the volumes are brittle and some appear to have been torn out.
    The diaries are arranged chronologically.
    - Diary, 1790 June 14-1800 February 21; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1800 February 21-1822 April 6; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1822 April 7-1848 April 27; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Transcripts, 1790-1848; 5 boxes
      - 1790-1801, undated; 12 folders (Box 4, Folder 1-12)
      - 1802-1816, undated; 15 folders (Box 5, Folder 1-15)
      - 1817-1832, undated; 16 folders (Box 6, Folder 1-16)
      - 1833-1844, undated; 12 folders (Box 7, Folder 1-12)
      - 1845-1848, undated; 4 folders (Box 8, Folder 1-4)
  - Subseries 1B: Reports, 1813-1817; 1 box 1 linear foot
    This subseries includes reports created by Green while he was president of the College of New Jersey. Reports were delivered to both the faculty and trustees of the college. The subject of the reports is the state of the college and the direction and goals of the school.
    The reports are arranged chronologically.
    - To the Faculty of the College of New Jersey, undated; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - To the Trustees of the College of New Jersey, 1813-1817; 3 folders (Box 8, Folder 6-8)
  - Subseries 1C: Sermons, 1786-1812; 2 boxes 22 linear feet
    This subseries consists of hand written and numbered sermons. The Bible passage on which Green was commenting is often noted. The run of sermons begins shortly after Green received his license to preach from the Presbytery of New Brunswick in 1786 and run to his being elected president of the College of New Jersey in 1812. The bulk of the sermons were preached to Green's congregation in Philadelphia.
    The sermons are arranged by number.
    - Sermon No. 6, 1786 August; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 9)
      handwritten, numbered
    - Sermon No. 8, 1789 February; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Sermon No. 14, undated; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 11)
      damaged
    - Sermon No. 23, 1787 September 9; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Sermon No. 28, 1787 November 17; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Sermon No. 67, 1788 November 23; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Sermon No. 77, 1789 March 22; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Sermon No. 80, 1789 March 19; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Sermon No. 89, 1789 August 30; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Sermon No. 90, 1789 September 19; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Sermon No. 139, 1791 March 27; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Sermon No. 141, 1791 April 17; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Sermon No. 152, 1791 October 16; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Sermon No. 198, 1793 March 10; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Sermon No. 209, 1793 August 11; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Sermon No. 237, 1796 February; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Sermon No. 252, 1797 July 16; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Sermon No. 253, 1797 July 30; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Sermon No. 256, 1797 November 30; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Sermon No. 262, 1798 June 3; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Sermons: Unnumbered, undated; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Sermons: Miscellaneous, 1791-1812; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Fragments, incomplete
  - Subseries 1D: Miscellaneous, 1764-1812; 1 box 1 linear foot
    This subseries contains several addresses written and delivered by Green and portions of The life of The Revd John Witherspoon, D.D., LL.D (New Brunswick, N.J.: Council of the Society of Colonial Wars of the State of New Jersey, c1973), which was a biography of College of New Jersey president and signer of the Declaration of Independence Dr. John Witherspoon. The addresses all appear to have been delivered during Green's tenure as president of the College of New Jersey. The material related to the "Life of Witherspoon" includes photostats of letters Green compiled while doing research and a galley proof copy of the index.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Address, 1812; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Delivered as a reply to a preceding Latin speech addressed to him by Dr. Samuel Miller, on the occasion of his inauguration as President of the College of New Jersey.
    - Addresses: Drafts, undated; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "Life of Witherspoon": Letters, 1764-1784; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 8)
      The life of The Revd John Witherspoon, D.D., LL.D was written by Ashbel Green and edited by Henry Lyttleton Savage. Included here are photostats of materials collected in preparation for the book.
    - "Life of Witherspoon": Index, undated; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Galley proof copy of index.
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1783-1841; 2 boxes 4 linear feet
  The series contains letters both to and from Ashbel Green. Correspondents include family, spouses, fellow clergy, friends, some of whom were members of prominent New Jersey families. Notable correspondents include Francis Scott Key, Benjamin Rush, and Jedediah Morse. The letters reveal details of Green's relationships with family and friends and sometimes offer glimpses into his professional experiences and philosophical beliefs.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - Abeel, John N, 1794-1805; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 10)
    10 ALsS by Ashbel Green
  - Alexander, Archibald, 1812 September 30; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 11)
    ALS by Ashbel Green
  - Anderson, Alexander, 1812 June 3; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 12)
    AMs memorandum by Ashbel Green
  - Armstrong, James F, 1794 November 19; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Beatty, Ercuries, 1818 July 2; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Beresford, Richard, 1787 June 21; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Bradford, Ebenezer, 1789 August 27; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 16)
    ALS to Ashbel Green
  - Bradford, James, 1808; 1825; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 17)
    ALS by Ashbel Green, ALS to Ashbel Green
  - Bradford, John M, 1804 February-July; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 18)
    ALS by Ashbel Green, Enclosed is excerpt from Dr. smith's lecture on marriage.
  - Bradford, Moses, 1783 October 17; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Bradford, William, Jr, 1789; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Bush, George, 1823 September 15; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Call, James, Jr.?, 1797 April 19; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 21A)
  - Chambers, George, 1816 March 14; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 22)
    ALS to Ashbel Green, requesting information about his brother's entrance to Princeton.
  - Clark, John F, 1815 February 20; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Classis, Reverend, 1799 January 17; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 24)
    ALS by Ashbel Green and William Falconer
  - Crichton, Joseph, 1835 October 22; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Croes, John, 1782 May 21-1783 July 8; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 26)
    3 ALsS by Ashbel Green
  - Davidson, Robert, 1806 February 24; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Darling, Eliza, 1809 March 21; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 28)
    ALS from Ashbel Green, includes typed transcript
  - Ewing, Charles, 1821 December 21; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Ewing, Greville, 1835 July 8; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 30)
    L by Ashbel Green, L to Ashbel Green, photostats
  - Finley, Robert, 1809 June 19; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 31)
    ALS to Ashbel Green, returning money allowed him as commissioner to the General Assembly
  - Freeman, Adam, 1801 October 24; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Giles, Aquila, 1818 August; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 33)
    2 ALsS by Ashbel Green
  - Green, Christiana Anderson, 1810 September 26-1813 May 24; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Green, Elizabeth Stockton, 1797 October 19-1803 July 28; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Green, Jacob (1722-1790), 1782 June-1786 February; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 36)
    ALS by Ashbel Green, 2 ALsS to Ashbel Green
  - Green, Jacob (1790-1841), 1808-1823; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 37)
    12 ALsS by Ashbel Green, 6 ALsS to Ashbel Green, includes notes from Ashbel on Jacob's professorship at Princeton
  - Green, James S, 1820 August 8; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Green, John Wickliffe, 1795 August 20; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Green, Mary McCulloh, 1815 September 20-1817 October 13; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 3)
    2 ALS by Ashbel Green
  - Green, Robert S, 1807 August 10; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Griffin, Edward D, 1801 January-1805 May; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 5)
    4 ALsS by Ashbel Green
  - Hill, William, 1804 January-May; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Hodge, Levi, 1820 March 20; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Janeway, Jacob J, 1817 February 7; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Key, Francis Scott, 1821 February 9; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Lewis, Zachariah, 1821 March-April; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Little, W.C., 1829 November 10; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Maclean, John, 1841 November 4; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Marx, Samuel, 1813 October 16; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - McCulloh, James W, 1819 February 9; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - McCulloh, Samuel, 1820-1837; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 15)
    ALS to Ashbel Green ,12 ALsS by Ashbel Green
  - McDowell, John, 1846 September 29; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 16)
    LS to Ashbel Green
  - Minto, Walter, 1795 May; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Morse, Jedediah, 1790-1820; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 18)
    7 ALsS by Ashbel Green
  - Ralston, Robert, 1819 January 7; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Richards, James, 1813-1822; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 20)
    ALS to Ashbel Green, 3 ALsS by Ashbel Green, TL by Ashbel Green
  - Romeyn, John B, 1813 August-September; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Rush, Dr. Benjamin, 1809 January 11; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Smith, R, 1816 December 12; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Smith, T.B., 1821 September 18; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 24)
    ALS to Ashbel Green, concerning 2 volumes of newspapers sent to the New Jersey College library.
  - Snowden, Charles, 1841 October 23; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Stockton, Job, 1809 October 14; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Stockton, Mrs. Richard, 1783 May; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 27)
    AMs by Ashbel Green, a poem
  - Stockton, Robert, 1797 April 24; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Thomson, William, 1802 October-1807 September; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 29)
    7 ALS to Ashbel Green, all Princeton-related.
  - Trustees of the College of New Jersey, 1822 September 26; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Vaughan, John, 1818 April 27; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Woodward, William, 1821 November 23; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Unidentified, January 4; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 33)
    ALS to Ashbel Green, concerning the dismissal of four students.
- Series 3: Papers of Other Persons, 1744-1958; 3 boxes 1.0 linear foot
  The series contains documents created by Ashbel's father Jacob and various other family and associates. This series contains two subseries: Jacob Green and Others. The Jacob Green subseries contains the writings of Ashbel's father while the Others subseries consists mostly of personal correspondence between family members.
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Subseries 3A: Jacob Green, 1744-1811; 2 boxes 6 linear feet
    This subseries contains the papers of Jacob Green. Materials include day books, diaries, and sermons. The day books and diaries document Jacob Green's daily activities. Green maintained a log of appointments, meetings, dates, and prayer activities. The sermons focus on specific Bible passages, which are noted on each. Green also noted each date the sermon was delivered. Some were read several times throughout his career.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by document type.
    - Address, 1768 December; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 34)
      "A Minister's Address..."
    - Day book, 1754 November 6-1755 May 8; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Day book, 1754 December 18-1755 April 30; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Diaries, 1751-1787; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Sermons, 1744-1769; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Sermons, 1770-1779; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Sermons, 1780-1790; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Sermons, 1765-1790; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Sermons, undated; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Sermons, undated; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1755-1811; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Draft, photocopied letters, notes
  - Subseries 3B: Others, 1783-1958; 1 box 4 linear feet
    This subseries consists of material created by family and colleagues of Ashbel Green. The bulk of the material relates to Ashbel's children, wives, and in-laws. Much of the correspondence between family is personal in nature. Since the material covers numerous members of the Green and McCulloh families, the dates range from before the birth of Ashbel to well after his death.
    The documents are arranged alphabetically by person.
    - Boudinot, Elias, circa 1783; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 1)
      ALS to Robert Stockton
    - Green, Ashbel, 1927 May 22; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Great grandson of Ashbel Green. ALS to "Sallie," his niece.
    - Green, Ashbel, Jr, 1828-1875; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 3)
      8 ALsS by Ashbel Green, Jr.
    - Green, Beverly Jean, 1958 August; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Last will and testament
    - Green, Jacob, 1819-1836; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Son of Ashbel Green. 9 receipts, 4 ALsS, 2 Ms
    - Green, James Sprout, 1800-1851; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 6)
      7 ALsS and notes on church and college property
    - Green, Mary McCulloh, undated; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 7)
      Order of processions at the funeral of the third Mrs. Ashbel Green
    - Green, Robert Stockton, circa 1850; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 8)
      College papers
    - McCulloh, Ann Smith, 1818 August; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 9)
      2 ALsS to Jacob Green (1790-1841)
    - McCulloh, James, undated; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 10)
      ALS to Jacob Green (1790-1841)
    - McCulloh, Margaret, 1822-1832; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 11)
      3 ALsS to Jacob Green (1790-1841)
    - McCulloh, Samuel, Jr, 1820-1841; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 12)
      9 ALsS to Samuel McCulloh and ALS to Margeret McCulloh
    - McCulloh, Sarah, 1870 April 20; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 13)
      ALS to Jacob Green
    - Miller, Elihu Spencer, 1850 July 1; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 14)
      ALS to James S. Green
    - Moffat, James C, 1835 December 30; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 15)
      ALS to John Sears McCulloh
    - Stockholm, John, 1780; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 16)
      Daybook
    - Unidentified, 1811; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Series 4: Miscellaneous, 1789-1858; 2 boxes 27 linear feet
  The series contains printed material and certified documents. Documents include affidavits, complaints, and certificates signed by Green and meeting minutes delivered to Green. The bulk of the documents date to Green's tenure at the College of New Jersey. The printed materials include two books written by Green and newspaper clippings.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Affidavit, 1817 January 22; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 18)
    Affidavit in regard to student riots at Princeton, DS by Ashbel Green and Elijah Slack
  - Bill of Complaint, circa 1807; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 19)